Rufus W. Weaver papers, Inclusive: 1906-1947, undated, Bulk: 1925-1945, undated
Baylor University, The Texas Collection
- Christianity and Culture, 1906-1947, undated; 3
  - Sermon: “The N.R.A. and the National Restoration of Adoration”, undated (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Sermon: “Nationalism, The Religious Rival of Evangelical Christianity”, circa 1930s (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Sermon: “The Pagan Elements in American Life”, undated (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Statement: “A Plea for the International Proscription of Religious Persecution”, undated (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Address: “Politics and Religion”, undated (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Notes on Churches and Society in Washington, DC, circa 1930s (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Letters and Notes on Franklin Roosevelt and Freedom of Religion, 1943 December 13, undated (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - “A Pronouncement Upon Religious Liberty”, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - Sermon: “The Relation of Our Christian Religion to Government”, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - Sermon Drafts: “Religion in the Congress”, circa 1930s (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Radio Address: “Religious Liberty”, 1940 January 20 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - Pamphlets: “Religious Liberty and American Baptists”, undated (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - “The Report of the Committee on Religious Liberty Made in the Joint Conference Committee on Public Relations”, 1946 October 2 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Pamphlet: “The Road to the Freedom of Religion”, circa 1944 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Notes on Roger Williams and Religious Liberty, undated (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Library of Congress Reading Room Slips and Address: “A Survey of Washington Baptist Conditions”, 1934 April 2, undated (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - Outline: “A Tentative Ten Year Campaign for Religious Freedom”, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - Pamphlets: “The Tocsin Sounds for American Baptists”, circa 1940s (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Statement to the Delegates of the United Nations Meeting in San Francisco, 1945 April 25 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Church-State Materials: Bulletin, Envelopes, and Notes, 1943-1944, undated (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Partial Drafts of Church-State Manuscripts, undated (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Address to the Inter-Church Club of Washington, DC: “The Vatican Envoy”, 1945-1946 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - “The Watchmen in Washington”, undated (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - “The World Crisis and Religious Liberty”, 1939 October 1 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Report: “Approaching Illiteracy as a National Problem”, circa 1920s (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Baccalaureate Address at the Baptist Bible Institute, 1925 May 8 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Report on the Georgia Baptist Convention, circa 1920s (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - “Baptist Faith and Principles as Interpreted by Our Baptist Fathers”, undated (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Biographical Items on Rufus W. Weaver, 1932-1943, undated (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - Pamphlets: “The Activities of the First Baptist Church, Sixteenth and O Streets N.W.”, 1935 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - Address: “Christian Education as Fostered by Southern Baptists During the Past Quarter of a Century”, circa 1930s (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - Sermon: “The Christianizing of Human Desires”, undated (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Church Minute Transcriptions (1802 March 14, 1802 March 21, and 1802 April 28), undated (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - “The Code of Sir Thomas Dale 1611”, undated (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - “Memorial of the Columbia Association of Baptist Churches to the Southern Baptist Convention at its Meeting in Memphis”, 1929 May 9 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - Drafts: “The Contact Point of Christianity”, undated (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - “The Co-Operation of Baptist Churches in the Twentieth Century”, undated (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - “Draft of Memorandum for Consideration of Committee of Twenty-One”, 1938 March 29 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - “The Valedictory of the [Southern Baptist] Education Board”, circa 1928 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Pamphlets: “The Emerging Issue: An Appeal to Our Baptist Democracy for its Earnest Consideration”, circa 1920s (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - “An Episode in Baptist History”, undated (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Transcriptions: “Extracts from Huckins’ Journal” (1840 January 19), undated (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence on M.C. Stith as Southern Baptist Superintendent of Missions in Washington, DC, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Drafts: Lecture at American University, 1931 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Lecture and Drafts: “The World League of Truth-Seekers”, 1931 December 8, undated (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - The Washington Post: Article on Luther Rice: “A Dreamer Came to Washington”, 1932 March 13 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Sermon: “National Repentance Precedes National Recovery”, circa 1930s (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Manuscript: “The Need for a New Dynamic in Re-Thinking Our Southern Baptist Program”, circa 1920s (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Address Drafts: Southern Baptist Convention: “The Present Outlook for Southern Baptists”, circa 1929 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Address Outline: “Re-Thinking Christianity or ‘De Mess Dat We’se In’”, undated (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Paper on the Need of Southern Baptist Churches for Education, undated (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Paper on the History of the First Baptist Church of Macon, Georgia, undated (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - “The Basic Thesis for a Christianized Philosophy”, undated (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Paper on Religion and Philosophy: “Summary”, undated (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Baccalaureate Address Drafts: “Solving Life’s Inescapable Problems”, 1925 June 9 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Pamphlets: “Southern Baptist and Illiteracy”, 1928 March 26 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Address: “Southern Baptists and the Post Apostolic Age”, circa 1930 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Article Drafts: “A Tale of Two Cities: Story of Greensboro and Its Other Days by Former Greensboro Citizens”, 1919 July 2, undated (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - “Report: Theological Education Survey Committee”, circa 1947 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Florida Baptist Witness: Article: “What About Tomorrow’s Church”, 1944 August 17 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - “William Melton Tryon: The Greatest of Texas Baptist Pioneer Preachers”, undated (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - Biography of Augustus Franklin Williams, undated (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Chapter 1 Draft: “Consciousness”, undated (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Bibliographies of Works on History, Philosophy, and Religion, undated (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - “What Is Christianity?”, undated (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - “The Philosophy of Religion”, undated (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Manuscript Drafts and Notes on Creative Idealization, Philosophy, Religion, and Values, undated (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - Notes on Philosophy of Religion, undated (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - “Notes for Graduate ClassDLPsychology of Religion: Introduction”, undated (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Outline: “The Psychological Bases of the Christian Faith”, undated (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Notes and Quotations on Religious Liberty, undated (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Mt. Auburn Baptist Church: Class in Christian Thought: Syllabus A: “The Logic of Christianity”, 1906-1907 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - “The Religious Problem of Today: Introduction”, undated (Box 6, Folder 37)
  - Drafts: “The Origin and Growth of Religion” and “Part I: Introduction, Historical and Preliminary Remarks: Chapter I: The Comparative History of Religion, Its Nature, Aims, and Methods”, undated (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - Chapter 4 Draft: “The Success and the Failure of American Evangelicals” and “The Ineffectiveness of American Evangelicals”, undated (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Draft: “The Propagation of the Historic Religions”, undated (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Notes on “The Religions”, undated (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Drafts: “The Search for Validity in Religion”, undated (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Draft: “A Survey of the Religious Condition of the World Today”, undated (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Notes on Baptists and Culture, undated (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Envelopes, Manuscript Drafts, Notes, and Printed Materials on Religion, 1928-1943 (Box 6, Folder 45)